<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom'>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html</id>
<title>FAQ's</title>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:28:19.133-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html' rel='self'/>
<entry>
<title type='text'>What if I have been divorced?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#What_if_I_have_been_divorced</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:28:19.133-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#What_if_I_have_been_divorced'/>
<content type='html'>
 If one or both members of the couple are divorced, documentation relating to each divorce will be required.  If you live and were divorced in Canada, you must bring the original or court certified copy of the final decree, final judgment or certificate of divorce to your local municipal office when you are purchasing the marriage license.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you live or were divorced outside of Canada, you may be required to submit documents to the provincial government several weeks prior to applying for a license.  Contact your local municipal office for further information or check the Ontario Government Website for additional requirements on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ontario.ca/en/life_events/married/012202&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Getting Married in Ontario &lt;/a&gt;after a divorce.  
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>We do not live in Toronto.  Do we need to come to Toronto to get a license?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#We_do_not_live_in_Toronto__Do_w</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:24:42.156-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#We_do_not_live_in_Toronto__Do_w'/>
<content type='html'>
 No. All municipalities in Ontario issue Marriage licenses.  You can apply in your local municipality; however one or both persons being married must make the application in person.
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>How do I obtain a Marriage License Application</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#How_do_I_obtain_a_Marriage_Lice</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:23:39.283-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#How_do_I_obtain_a_Marriage_Lice'/>
<content type='html'>
 You can apply for a Marriage License no more than three months prior to your wedding date.  The marriage license is valid anywhere in Ontario for three months from the date of purchase.  A Marriage License can be obtained from the clerk of most cities, townships, towns or villages. Check your municipal blue pages or one can be downloaded from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.orgforms.gov.on.ca/eForms/start.do?lang=en&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Government of Ontario Website&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Either or both of the persons being married must apply in person to the Marriage License Issuer to obtain a license. They will need to bring identification, such as a birth certificate (along with any change of name certificates), current passport, Record of Immigrant Landing or Canadian citizenship card, along with photo identification, for both persons.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;There is a set fee for purchasing a Marriage License.  Contact your municipal office for the current fee. 
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>What does the Officiant wear while conducting the ceremony?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#What_does_the_Officiant_wear_wh</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:18:36.662-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#What_does_the_Officiant_wear_wh'/>
<content type='html'>
 When performing the ceremony I wear clothing that fits the atmosphere of the occasion.  A more formal dress for a traditional wedding; a less formal suit for a more relaxed wedding.  I do not wear standard clerical attire. 
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>What arrangements are in place in the event the Officiant is unable to perform the ceremony?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#What_arrangements_are_in_place_</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:16:44.836-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#What_arrangements_are_in_place_'/>
<content type='html'>
 I am part of a network of humanist Officiants who have agreed to stand in for each other in the event of unforeseen circumstances.  As a group, we ensure that couples contracting our services will have their ceremony performed at the designated time and place. 
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>Does the Officant attend the reception?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#Does_the_Officant_attend_the_re</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:14:45.327-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#Does_the_Officant_attend_the_re'/>
<content type='html'>
 There is no expectation that I will attend your wedding wedding meal or reception however sometimes the couple will extend an invitation to the Officiant to attend the reception or dinner and extend good wishes to everyone who will be coming together to share the meal, which I am happy to do.  
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>When does the officiant arrive and leave?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#When_does_the_officiant_arrive_</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:13:19.710-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#When_does_the_officiant_arrive_'/>
<content type='html'>
 I try to arrive approximately 30 minutes prior to the ceremony and leave about 30 minutes after and am available for contact right up to the ceremony via my cell phone. 
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>
<entry>
<title type='text'>How Long is the average wedding?</title>
<id>http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#How_Long_is_the_average_wedding</id>
<updated>2009-05-18T02:10:09.842-04:00</updated>
<link href='http://www.lifedeservesceremonies.com/FAQ/FAQ.html#How_Long_is_the_average_wedding'/>
<content type='html'>
 The average length of a wedding is from 15-20 minutes however the length will vary depending on the words, readings, rituals and music that is chosen by the couple. 
 </content>
<author><name>FaqMaker</name></author>
 </entry>

</feed>
